<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd">
<collection><source>PMC</source><date>20201220</date><key>pmc.key</key><document><id>5340372</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">Low cord vitamin D associated with poor infant lung function</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0173268</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">5340372</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">28267792</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">PONE-D-16-24976</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e0173268</infon><infon key="issue">3</infon><infon key="license">This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lai;given-names:Shen-Hao</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liao;given-names:Sui-Ling</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Lai;given-names:Shen-Hao</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tsai;given-names:Ming-Han</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hua;given-names:Man-Chin</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chiu;given-names:Chih-Yung</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yeh;given-names:Kuo-Wei</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Yao;given-names:Tsung-Chieh</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Huang;given-names:Jing-Long</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Chin;given-names:Wei-Chun</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Lai;given-names:Shen-Hao</infon><infon key="notes">All relevant data are within the paper.</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">Data Availability</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>0</offset><text>Low cord-serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with poor lung function performance and increased respiratory infection in infancy</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>140</offset><text>Background</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>151</offset><text>Perinatal vitamin D deficiency is associated with a higher risk of wheezing in childhood. However, the relationship between vitamin D levels and lung function in infancy has not been investigated. The aim of this study was to investigate the impact of perinatal vitamin D levels on respiratory function and disease outcome in infancy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>486</offset><text>Materials and methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>508</offset><text>Full-term infants without any chronic diseases or major anomalies were enrolled in the Prediction of Allergies in Taiwanese Children cohort study. Maternal and cord blood were collected for determining the 25(OH)D level. Questionnaires were recorded at birth and 6 months of age. Infant lung function, including tidal breathing analysis, respiratory mechanics, and forced tidal expiration, was tested at 6 months of age.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>929</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>937</offset><text>A total of 122 mother—infant pairs were enrolled in this study, and 71 infants underwent lung function testing at 6 months of age. 25(OH)D levels in maternal and cord serum were highly correlated (r2 = 0.457, p &lt; 0.0001). Infants with lower cord serum 25(OH)D levels (&lt; 13.7 ng/ml) had higher resistance of respiratory system (p &lt; 0.01) and a higher risk of a respiratory tract infection before the age of 6 months (p &lt; 0.01).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>1366</offset><text>Conclusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1377</offset><text>Although a high correlation was found between maternal and cord vitamin D levels, the effect on respiratory outcome was different. Our study is the first to show that low cord 25(OH)D levels significantly relationship with poorer lung function performance and higher likelihood of a respiratory tract infection before 6 months of age.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>1712</offset><text>Introduction</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>1725</offset><text>Vitamin D is crucial not only for calcium metabolism and skeletal health but also in the homeostasis of many other systems. Since the discovery that most tissues and cells have vitamin D receptors, there has been great interest in its role in the development of many diseases, such as cancer, cardiovascular diseases, infectious diseases, and autoimmune disease.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2088</offset><text>Camargo et al. reported an inverse correlation between prenatal vitamin D intake and recurrent wheezing of offspring. Measurements of vitamin D serum level 25-hydroxyvitamin D [25(OH)D] have yielded conflicting results regarding the relationship between maternal- or cord-blood levels and subsequent asthma development. However, Baiz et al. and Camargo et al. have recently shown that infants with low cord serum vitamin D levels have a higher risk of childhood wheezing.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2560</offset><text>Although episodes of wheezing during childhood are mostly caused by a viral respiratory infection, their detailed pathogenesis and relationship with asthma are unclear. Martinez et al. classified childhood wheezing into four distinct phenotypes: no wheezing, transient early wheezing, late-onset wheezing, and persistent wheezing. In the study, the majority of infants with transient early wheezing had diminished airway function in early life. A recent study further revealed that cord serum 25(OH)D levels were inversely correlated with the risk of transient early wheezing. However, the relationship between vitamin D levels and respiratory function during infancy has not yet been clarified.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3256</offset><text>The primary purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of perinatal vitamin D levels on the performance of respiratory function in infancy. The secondary objective was to further clarify the effect on the risk of eczema, wheezing, and respiratory tract infections in early life.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>3544</offset><text>Materials and methods</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>3566</offset><text>Study population and data collection</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>3603</offset><text>Records were obtained from an ongoing prospective birth cohort study called the Prediction of Allergy in Taiwanese Children (PATCH), from January 2013 to December 2015. PATCH is an unselected, population-based birth cohort study investigating the risk factors for immune-related and allergic diseases in children in Keelung, a city in northern Taiwan. Detailed descriptions of the recruitment and data collection have been reported previously. The Chang Gung Ethics Committee approved the study, and written informed consent was obtained from the parents or legal guardians of the neonates. Neonates born prematurely (gestational age &lt; 37 weeks), those with major birth defects or congenital structural anomalies of the upper airway, those who were hemodynamically unstable, and those with a history of severe lower airway infection with intensive care admission, were excluded from the study.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4497</offset><text>Standard questionnaires on atopic heredity, smoke exposure, and atopic symptoms were answered by parents or legal guardians at birth and 6 months. Serum from mother—cord pairs was collected and frozen for later measurement of 25(OH)D. Examinations of infant lung function were performed at 6 months of age. All participants’ records and clinical information were anonymized and deidentified before analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>4909</offset><text>Analysis of serum 25(OH)D</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4935</offset><text>The levels of 25(OH)D were determined by an automated electrochemiluminescence immunoassay (Roche Diagnostics, Mannheim, Germany) in the core lab at Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, which is accredited by the College of American Pathologists. The assay has shown good correlation with standard reference results from liquid-chromatography tandem mass spectrometry. In-house precision testing yielded intra-assay coefficients of variation (CVs) of 3.7% and 3.4% at 15 and 32 ng/mL, respectively, and inter-assay CVs of 7.9% and 5.4% at 17 and 33 ng/mL, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5498</offset><text>Bacterial culture of nasopharyngeal swab</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5539</offset><text>At 1 month of age, specimens were collected through the nose with a cotton-tipped swab (Copan Swab Applicator, Copan Diagnostics, Brescia, Italy). Specimens were sent to our microbiology lab for standard bacterial cultures within 2 hours of collection. In addition, multiplex PCR was performed for detecting Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae, Moraxella catarrhalis, Streptococcus pyogens, and Staphylococcus aureus.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>5970</offset><text>Infant lung function testing</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5999</offset><text>Measurements were taken of healthy infants who had had no respiratory tract infection for at least 3 weeks. Before the tests, body weight was measured and crown—heel length was obtained on a measuring board. Since there were few adverse events being reported, chloral hydrate has been the preferred medication for infant lung function tests for over 20 years at US and Europe. Therefore, the infants were then sedated with oral chloral hydrate (50–75 mg/kg) and placed in the supine position, with the neck mildly extended. The oxygen saturation and heart rate of participants were monitored with pulse oximeter during the procedure and until they became fully awake. Infant lung function testing was performed with the Jaeger Masterscreen BabyBody Paediatrics System (CareFusion, Höchberg, Germany), which conforms with the American Thoracic Society and European Respiratory Society recommendations. Detailed procedures and data collection of tidal breathing analysis, respiratory mechanics, and forced tidal expiration were stated in our previous study.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7060</offset><text>The ratio of time to reach peak expiratory flow to total expiratory time (Tpef/Te) in the tidal breathing analysis, the resistance and compliance of the respiratory system (Rrs and Crs) in respiratory mechanics, and the maximal expiratory flow at functional residual capacity (VmaxFRC) in forced tidal expiration were collected for further analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>7410</offset><text>Statistical analysis</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7431</offset><text>Results were expressed as a mean ± standard error. Comparisons between groups were performed using student t-test for continuous variables, and Fisher exact test for categorical variables. A simple linear regression was used to determine the correlation of 25(OH)D levels between maternal and cord serum. To compare the difference in outcomes between low and high 25(OH)D level of maternal/cord serum, groups with low and high level were further categorized according to the mean 25(OH)D value. The effect of high/low 25(OH)D was corrected for the effects of other independent risk factors of dependent variables. First, Pearson’s correlation was used to evaluate the relationship between dependent variables and each of the independent variables (Tables 1 and 2). Predictors with p level ≤ 0.1 were further includes in multivariate logistic or linear regression analysis. p &lt;0.05 was considered statistically significant. All analyses were performed using IBM SPSS software v. 20 (Armonk, NY, USA).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>8436</offset><text>Demographic data, family and environmental data, outcomes, and infant lung function in groups with different 25(OH)D status of cord serum.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low cord 25(OH)D (n = 36)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High cord 25(OH)D (n = 35)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Demographic data&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Gestational age (weeks)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;38.6 ± 1.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;38.4 ± 1.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Male (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;36*&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;59&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Nature delivery (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;67&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;63&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Birth BW (kg)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.1 ± 0.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.0 ± 0.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Birth BL (cm)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50.4 ± 2.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;49.8 ± 1.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BW (kg)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.3 ± 1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.3 ± 1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL (cm)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;68.8 ± 3.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;68.2 ± 2.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;% of fall/winter birth&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;47.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;46.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Family and environmental data&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Asthma, mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Asthma, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AR mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;37.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AR, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AD, mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;16.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AD, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Daycare attendance (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Maternal smoke in pregnancy (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Postnatal smoke Exposure (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;44.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;42.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Outcomes&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NP colonization rate (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;69.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;62.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ever RTI till 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;40.0**&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Eczema at 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ever wheeze at 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Infant lung function&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;% of T&lt;sub&gt;pef&lt;/sub&gt;/T&lt;sub&gt;e&lt;/sub&gt; &amp;lt;0.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Rrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.18 ± -0.37**&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.10 ± 0.29&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Crs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.19 ± 0.86&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.20± 1.20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Vmax&lt;sub&gt;FRC&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.02 ± 1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.17 ± 1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>8575</offset><text>	Low cord 25(OH)D (n = 36)	High cord 25(OH)D (n = 35)	 	Demographic data			 	Gestational age (weeks)	38.6 ± 1.1	38.4 ± 1.7	 	Male (%)	36*	59	 	Nature delivery (%)	67	63	 	Birth BW (kg)	3.1 ± 0.4	3.0 ± 0.3	 	Birth BL (cm)	50.4 ± 2.4	49.8 ± 1.9	 	BW (kg)	8.3 ± 1.0	8.3 ± 1.0	 	BL (cm)	68.8 ± 3.6	68.2 ± 2.2	 	% of fall/winter birth	47.1	46.8	 	Family and environmental data	 	Asthma, mother	2.8	5.7	 	Asthma, father	2.8	2.8	 	AR mother	22.2	37.1	 	AR, father	30.6	22.9	 	AD, mother	16.7	8.6	 	AD, father	0	5.7	 	Daycare attendance (%)	13.9	11.4	 	Maternal smoke in pregnancy (%)	2.8	5.7	 	Postnatal smoke Exposure (%)	44.4	42.9	 	Outcomes			 	NP colonization rate (%)	69.7	62.0	 	Ever RTI till 6 months (%)	40.0**	11.1	 	Eczema at 6 months (%)	19	14	 	Ever wheeze at 6 months (%)	11	18	 	Infant lung function			 	% of Tpef/Te &lt;0.2	14	23	 	Z score of Rrs	-0.18 ± -0.37**	0.10 ± 0.29	 	Z score of Crs	-0.19 ± 0.86	-0.20± 1.20	 	Z score of VmaxFRC	0.02 ± 1.0	-0.17 ± 1.0	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>9560</offset><text>BW, body weight; BL, body length; AR, allergic rhinitis; AD, atopic dermatitis; NP, nasopharyngeal cavity; RTI, respiratory tract infection, Tpef/Te, ratio of time to peak expiratory flow to total expiratory time; Rrs, resistance of respiratory system; Crs, compliance of respiratory system; VmaxFRC, maximal expiratory flow at functional residual capacity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t001.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t001</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>9918</offset><text>* p &lt;0.05, and ** p &lt; 0.01 comparing “High cord 25(OH)D” group.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t002.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>9986</offset><text>Demographic data, family and environmental data, outcomes, and infant lung function in groups with different 25(OH)D status of maternal serum.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t002.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low maternal 25(OH)D (n = 36)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High maternal 25(OH)D (n = 35)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Demographic data&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Gestational age (weeks)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;38.4 ± 1.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;38.8 ± 1.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Male (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;49&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Nature delivery (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;66&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Birth BW (kg)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.1 ± 0.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;3.2 ± 0.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Birth BL (cm)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50.6 ± 2.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;50.4 ± 2.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BW (kg)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.3 ± 1.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.1± 1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;BL (cm)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;69.0 ± 2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;68.6 ± 3.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;% of fall/winter birth&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;38.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;51.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Family and environmental data&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Asthma, mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Asthma, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AR mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;31.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AR, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;30.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;31.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AD, mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;13.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AD, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Daycare attendance (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;11.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;14.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Maternal smoke in pregnancy (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;8.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Postnatal smoke Exposure (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;41.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;37.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Outcomes&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NP colonization rate (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;69.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;66.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ever RTI till 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;22.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Eczema at 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ever wheeze at 6 months (%)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;&lt;italic&gt;Infant lung function&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:thick&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;% of T&lt;sub&gt;pef&lt;/sub&gt;/T&lt;sub&gt;e&lt;/sub&gt; &amp;lt; 0.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Rrs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.04 ± 0.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.04 ± 0.39&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Crs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.03 ± 1.13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.39 ± 1.08&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Vmax&lt;sub&gt;FRC&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.07 ± 1.01&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.24 ± 1.09&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>10129</offset><text>	Low maternal 25(OH)D (n = 36)	High maternal 25(OH)D (n = 35)	 	Demographic data			 	Gestational age (weeks)	38.4 ± 1.2	38.8 ± 1.3	 	Male (%)	50	49	 	Nature delivery (%)	66	62	 	Birth BW (kg)	3.1 ± 0.3	3.2 ± 0.4	 	Birth BL (cm)	50.6 ± 2.1	50.4 ± 2.5	 	BW (kg)	8.3 ± 1.1	8.1± 1.0	 	BL (cm)	69.0 ± 2.8	68.6 ± 3.3	 	% of fall/winter birth	38.9	51.4	 	Family and environmental data			 	Asthma, mother	2.8	8.6	 	Asthma, father	2.8	0	 	AR mother	22.2	31.4	 	AR, father	30.6	31.4	 	AD, mother	13.9	8.6	 	AD, father	0	2.8	 	Daycare attendance (%)	11.1	14.3	 	Maternal smoke in pregnancy (%)	8.3	2.8	 	Postnatal smoke Exposure (%)	41.6	37.1	 	Outcomes			 	NP colonization rate (%)	69.7	66.7	 	Ever RTI till 6 months (%)	25.0	22.8	 	Eczema at 6 months (%)	17	20	 	Ever wheeze at 6 months (%)	25	23	 	Infant lung function			 	% of Tpef/Te &lt; 0.2	25	9	 	Z score of Rrs	-0.04 ± 0.33	-0.04 ± 0.39	 	Z score of Crs	-0.03 ± 1.13	-0.39 ± 1.08	 	Z score of VmaxFRC	0.07 ± 1.01	-0.24 ± 1.09	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t002.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t002</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>11119</offset><text>BW, body weight; BL, body length; AR, allergic rhinitis; AD, atopic dermatitis; NP, nasopharyngeal cavity; RTI, respiratory tract infection, Tpef/Te, ratio of time to peak expiratory flow to total expiratory time; Rrs, resistance of respiratory system; Crs, compliance of respiratory system; VmaxFRC, maximal expiratory flow at functional residual capacity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>11477</offset><text>Results</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>11485</offset><text>Subjects and demographic data</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11515</offset><text>From the original 201 neonates enrolled in the study, 122 pairs of maternal-cord serum were collected (Fig 1). Examinations of infant lung function were successfully performed for 71 infants at 6 months of age. In these sessions, 71 maneuvers of tidal breathing analysis, 65 maneuvers of respiratory mechanics, and 59 maneuvers of tidal forced expiration were eligible for the final analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.g001.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.g001</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>11908</offset><text>Study flow chart.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>11926</offset><text>Among the 71 infants, 36 were boys. The mean gestational age of enrolled infants was 38.5 ± 1.3 weeks, and 63.4% of the infants were delivered naturally. The mean body weight and body length at birth were 3.0 ± 0.6 kg and 48.4 ± 9.9 cm respectively. At the time of the lung function testing, the mean body weight was 8.3 ± 1.0 kg, and the mean body length was 68.6 ± 3.0 cm.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12306</offset><text>25(OH)D levels of maternal-cord pairs</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12344</offset><text>Among the 122 specimens collected, the mean 25(OH)D levels in the maternal and cord serum were 14.4 ± 6.5 and 14.0 ± 6.6 ng/ml, respectively. There was a significant positive correlation between maternal and cord serum 25(OH)D levels (r2 = 0.457, p &lt; 0.0001; Fig 2). The mean 25(OH)D level of the 71 infants who successfully underwent later infant lung function testing was 13.8 ± 6.3 ng/ml, and that of their mothers was 15.0 ± 6.1 ng/ml, which were also significantly correlated (r2 = 0.468, p &lt; 0.0001).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.g002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.g002</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_title_caption</infon><offset>12855</offset><text>Correlation between maternal and cord serum 25(OH)D levels.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12915</offset><text>Lung function and outcome vs 25(OH)D levels</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12959</offset><text>To compare the effect of cord 25(OH)D level on lung function at 6 months of age, we defined those with cord 25(OH)D level ≥ 13.8 ng/ml as the “high cord 25(OH)D” group, and the rest as the “low cord 25(OH)D” group. In addition, maternal 25D(OH) level ≥15.0 ng/ml was described as “high maternal 25(OH)D” and &lt;15.0 ng/ml as “low maternal 25(OH)D.”</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>13326</offset><text>A significant difference in the Rrs was found between the high and low cord 25(OH)D groups (3.8 ± 0.8 vs. 4.4 ± 1.0 kPa*s/L, p &lt; 0.01). However, no differences were noted in the Crs and VmaxFRC between the two groups (high vs. low: Crs, 97.5 ± 28.6 vs. 98.1 ± 27.8 mL/kPa; VmaxFRC, 191 ± 90 vs. 210 ± 92 mL/s). No difference in the ratio of Tpef/Te &lt; 0.2 was found between both groups. After adjusting for body length and comparing with a local reference, the high cord 25(OH)D group still had significantly lower Rrs than did the low cord 25(OH)D group (Table 1). However, no differences were noted in the various parameters of lung function between high and low maternal 25(OH)D groups (Table 2).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14031</offset><text>Among the 71 infants who underwent infant lung function testing, bacterial cultures from nasopharyngeal specimens were taken from 66 infants, with a positive culture rate of 68.2% (45/66). Majority of the positive cultures showed growth for Staphylococcus aureus, except for one was Moraxella catarrhalis. No differences were seen in the nasopharyngeal bacteria colonization rate between the low and high 25(OH)D groups of the maternal or cord serum. Although the incidence of infant wheeze was similar between the groups, the percentage of respiratory tract infection was significantly higher in infants with a low cord serum 25(OH)D level (Table 1).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14683</offset><text>Based on the lung function and outcome of the analysis in Table 1, we had then used those relatively significant variables (p ≤ 0.1) to determine independent predictors with multivariate linear or logistical regression. The analysis showed that high cord 25(OH)D was the strongest predictor of good lung function performance (Table 3), and vice versa, low cord level predicted poor lung function outcome. Meanwhile, paternal history with allergic rhinitis and maternal smoke in pregnancy also had adverse effect on lung function. However, low cord 25(OH)D alone was the only predicted higher probability of respiratory infection in the first 6 months of life (Table 4).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>15355</offset><text>Multiple linear regression analysis of lung function outcome (Z score of Rrs).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Beta (s.e.)&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot; rid=&quot;t003fn002&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;#&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;t&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;p value&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;High cord 25(OH)D&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.252 (0.088)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;2.736&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.005&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;AR, father&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.232 (0.103)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-2.416&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.018&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Maternal smoke in pregnancy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.396 (0.196)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-2.024&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.032&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;NP colonization&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.121 (0.90)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-1.353&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.182&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Male&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.109 (0.087)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-1.255&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.215&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Asthma, mother&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.144 (0.152)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;-0.946&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.348&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;(Constant)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.110 (0.102)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.082&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.284&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;italic&gt;R&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;italic&gt;2&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; = &lt;italic&gt;0&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;italic&gt;293&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>15434</offset><text>	Beta (s.e.)#	t	p value	 	High cord 25(OH)D	0.252 (0.088)	2.736	0.005	 	AR, father	-0.232 (0.103)	-2.416	0.018	 	Maternal smoke in pregnancy	-0.396 (0.196)	-2.024	0.032	 	NP colonization	-0.121 (0.90)	-1.353	0.182	 	Male	-0.109 (0.087)	-1.255	0.215	 	Asthma, mother	-0.144 (0.152)	-0.946	0.348	 	(Constant)	0.110 (0.102)	1.082	0.284	 	R2 = 0.293				 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>15786</offset><text>AR, allergic rhinitis; NP, nasopharyngeal cavity.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t003.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t003</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>15836</offset><text># Beta (s.e.), regression coefficient (standard error)</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t004.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t004</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_title_caption</infon><offset>15891</offset><text>Multivariate logistic regression analysis for clinical outcome (ever RTI till 6 months of age).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t004.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t004</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; valign=&quot;middle&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;OR&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;95% CI&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;p value&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Low cord 25(OH)D&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;7.613&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.71–33.89&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;bold&gt;0.008&lt;/bold&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Z score of Vmax&lt;sub&gt;FRC&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.729&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.846–3.533&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.133&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Ever eczema at 6 months&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.322&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.034–3.033&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.322&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Postnatal smoke exposure&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.576&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.402–6.172&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.514&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Male&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.454&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.105–1.966&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;char&quot; char=&quot;.&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;0.454&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>15987</offset><text>	OR	95% CI	p value	 	Low cord 25(OH)D	7.613	1.71–33.89	0.008	 	Z score of VmaxFRC	1.729	0.846–3.533	0.133	 	Ever eczema at 6 months	0.322	0.034–3.033	0.322	 	Postnatal smoke exposure	1.576	0.402–6.172	0.514	 	Male	0.454	0.105–1.966	0.454	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">pone.0173268.t004.xml</infon><infon key="id">pone.0173268.t004</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>16238</offset><text>OR, odd ratio; CI, confidence interval.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>16278</offset><text>Discussion</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16289</offset><text>A positive correlation was found between 25(OH)D levels in the serum of mother and child in this prospective birth cohort study. This is the first report to show that low cord—and not maternal—serum 25(OH)D levels contribute to relatively poor lung performance at 6 months of age. An increased risk for a respiratory tract infection before the age of 6 months was also found in infants with low cord 25(OH)D level. However, no differences were found in the incidence of wheeze and eczema or the rate of nasopharyngeal bacterial colonization between the groups with high and low 25(OH)D levels of mother—cord serum pairs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>16916</offset><text>Infants who were exclusively breastfed or had high levels of skin pigmentation, inadequate sunlight exposure, or inadequate vitamin supplement are at risk of a vitamin D deficiency. Although a circulating level of 25(OH)D less than 20 ng/mL is defined as vitamin D deficiency, the mean levels may vary among different populations. In previous studies, mean 25(OH)D levels were generally higher than 20 ng/ml in maternal serum. However, cord serum levels ranged widely from 10.95 to 34.4 ng/mL. In this study, the mean 25(OH)D level in the cord serum (13.8 ng/mL) was comparable with other reports, but a lower mean level in the maternal serum (15.0 ng/mL) was observed. These suboptimal levels were also seen in recent reports by Liao et al. Nevertheless, fair correlations between mother and cord blood were found in previous and this study as well.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17767</offset><text>Animal studies have found that vitamin D deficiency can cause deficits in lung function, which can be explained by a change in lung development. Similarly, in a large birth cohort study, infants with low cord serum 25(OH)D had a higher risk of transient wheeze before the age of 5 years. The COPSAC2000 study have failed to show an association between cord 25(OH)D level and lung function at 7 years of age. Also no association was also found between a children’s vitamin D levels and their lung function at 6–7 years of age in the KOALA birth cohort study. However, in contrary to these reports, a survey in Canadian children showed that both low and high vitamin D levels were related to increased risk of wheeze and reduced performance of lung function. However, comparing to our study, the median level of cord 25(OH)D of COPSAC2000 was relatively high (19 ng/ml). Furthermore, instead of measuring cord serum 25(OH)D, both KOALA and Canadian studies determined the level of 25(OH)D during preschool or school age. Regarding to the relationship between 25(OH)D and lung function in adults, the HUNT study revealed that low serum 25(OH)D level was not associated with airway obstruction in most asthma adults with the exception of males with asthma but without allergic rhinitis. Therefore, drawing conclusions about the effects of perinatal and postnatal vitamin D status from these results can be difficult. In this study, although cord serum 25(OH)D level was not associated with higher risk of wheeze at 6 months, it is related with increased respiratory resistance. Furthermore, it is worth noticing that the increased airway resistance may result in a higher risk of wheezing in early childhood.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>19476</offset><text>Infant lung function testing has been widely used in research and clinical practices. Several tests, including the analysis of tidal breathing, mechanics of respiratory system, flow-volume curves of forced expiration, and measurement of lung volume, were used to evaluate respiratory function. The ratio Tpef/Te, the resistance of the respiratory system and the flow of tidal forced expiration are related to respiratory function in infants with recurrent wheezing, asthma, and bronchiolitis.. Measurements of resistance and forced expiration are the most commonly used maneuvers to assess airway function. During resistance measurements, which include intra, extrathoracic, and pulmonary resistance, the extrathoracic airway resistance dominates in obligatory nasal breathing infants. By comparison, forced expiration maneuvers more closely reflect the function of the intrathoracic airway. In this study, infants with low 25(OH)D had higher Rrs but similar VmaxFRC, which implies that low perinatal vitamin D levels might be associated with a higher resistance of the extrathoracic airway.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20568</offset><text>The fetal vitamin D status is dependent on the placental-fetal circulation. Though, the interpretation of serum 25(OH)D level may be complicated by the presence of C3-epimer of 25(OH)D [C3-epi-25(OH)D], a vitamin metabolite that may be erroneously included as 25(OH)D by LC-MS and immunoassay methods. C3-epi-25(OH)D has lower affinity for the vitamin D receptor, thus it own lower bio-function than 25(OH)D in vivo. Bailey et al had discovered that, after transplacental circulation, the concentration of C3-epi-25(OH)D was significant higher in infants than mother. Therefore, the high concentration of C3-epi-25(OH)D in infants may explain that low cord—but not maternal—serum 25(OH)D levels contribute to poor lung function and increased risk of respiratory infection in this study.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21359</offset><text>Recent studies have shown that vitamin D can directly stimulate several immune cells and can promote the production of antimicrobial peptides. Expression of cathelicidin, an antimicrobial peptide, can be augmented by lung epithelial cells under the stimulation of vitamin D. In asthmatic children, episodes of acute exacerbation relating to respiratory infection were also inversely associated with serum 25(OH)D levels. In a randomized control trial, a vitamin D supplement can even decrease the risk of seasonal flu in children. Because of substantial antibody levels from transplacental transmission, infants are less likely to get respiratory infection before 6 months of age. Furthermore, Camargo et al. has shown that infants with low cord serum 25(OH)D levels have a higher risk of respiratory tract infection before the age of 3 months. However, the exact association between single cord-serum vitamin D level and postnatal immunity is unclear. More investigation is required to further understand the role of vitamin D for the prevention of respiratory tract infection in infancy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>22449</offset><text>There are some potential limitations to our findings. First, in cause of the difficulties in performing infant lung function testing, relatively small number of mother-infant pairs was enrolled in this study. In post hoc analysis of two-tail t test, the statistical power could reach 0.6 (alpha risk, 0.05; effect size, 0.5). In addition, in the regression model for analysis of predictors, the power still can achieve as high as 0.8 (alpha risk, 0.05; effect size f2, 0.15). Second, our previous report concluded that relatively low vitamin D levels were common in the PATCH population sample of children and young adults with an inverse correlation between 25(OH)D level and age being shown here. The majority of the participants lived in Keelung, a rainy city whose inhabitants have a higher risk of vitamin D deficiency than elsewhere due to lack of sun exposure. In our study, the mean 25(OH)D level of the maternal serum was low, at 15 ng/ml, which might hinder our investigation. Third, a large percentage of infants in the low cord 25(OH)D group were male, although our previous study found no gender difference in the infant lung function test. Furthermore, the measurement of respiratory mechanics relies on both the absence of airflow and the invocation of the Hering—Breuer reflex while occluding the air outflow. Although this technique is relatively noninvasive and easy to perform, there is limited evidence showing that the Rrs is sensitive enough to distinguish between different groups of infants with various clinical conditions. Therefore, defining the causal relationship between Rrs and clinical outcomes in infants with low cord serum 25(OH)D levels is difficult. Last, the sample size was rather small, and the vitamin D levels of the participants were generally suboptimal in our study. Although poor lung function performance and an increased risk of respiratory tract infection were related to relatively low cord serum vitamin D levels, further extrapolating the effects of vitamin D on the respiratory function of the general infant population might still be difficult.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24550</offset><text>In conclusion, this study is the first to reveal that infants with low cord serum 25(OH)D levels have poorer lung function at 6 months of age compared with those with high levels. They also have a higher risk of a respiratory tract infection before this age. Although cord vitamin D levels are strongly correlated with maternal vitamin D levels, the extent of the impact on later respiratory function is distinctive. We believe that this study provides a clearer understanding of the effect of perinatal vitamin D levels on respiratory function and respiratory outcome in infancy.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>25131</offset><text>References</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">9</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Trump;given-names:DL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Deeb;given-names:KK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Johnson;given-names:CS</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1097/PPO.0b013e3181c51ee6</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20164683</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cancer J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>25142</offset><text>Vitamin D: considerations in the continued development as an agent for cancer prevention and therapy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1540</infon><infon key="lpage">1544</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kim;given-names:DH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sabour;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sagar;given-names:UN</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Adams;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Whellan;given-names:DJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2008.06.067</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19026311</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Cardiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">102</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>25243</offset><text>Prevalence of hypovitaminosis D in cardiovascular diseases (from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 2001 to 2004)</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">384</infon><infon key="lpage">390</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ginde;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mansbach;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2008.560</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19237723</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Intern Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">169</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>25375</offset><text>Association between serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D level and upper respiratory tract infection in the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">255</infon><infon key="lpage">257</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kinder;given-names:BW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hagaman;given-names:JT</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1586/eci.11.12</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21595589</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Expert Rev Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>25527</offset><text>Could combating vitamin D deficiency reduce the incidence of autoimmune disease?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">788</infon><infon key="lpage">795</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rifas-Shiman;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Litonjua;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rich-Edwards;given-names:JW</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Weiss;given-names:ST</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Gold;given-names:DR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17344501</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Clin Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">85</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>25608</offset><text>Maternal intake of vitamin D during pregnancy and risk of recurrent wheeze in children at 3 y of age</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">215.e1</infon><infon key="lpage">7</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Carroll;given-names:KN</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Gebretsadik;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Larkin;given-names:EK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dupont;given-names:WD</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Liu;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Van Driest;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2011.04.002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21658670</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Obstet Gynecol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">205</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>25709</offset><text>Relationship of maternal vitamin D level with maternal and infant respiratory disease</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e180</infon><infon key="lpage">187</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ingham;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wickens;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Thadhani;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Silvers;given-names:KM</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Epton;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1542/peds.2010-0442</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21187313</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatrics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">127</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>25795</offset><text>Cord-blood 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and risk of respiratory infection, wheezing, and asthma</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">950</infon><infon key="lpage">956</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pike;given-names:KC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Inskip;given-names:HM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Robinson;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lucas;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Cooper;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Harvey;given-names:NC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-201888</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22707522</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Thorax</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">67</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>25889</offset><text>Maternal late-pregnancy serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D in relation to childhood wheeze and atopic outcomes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">220</infon><infon key="lpage">228</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Weisse;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Winkler;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Hirche;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Herberth;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hinz;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bauer;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/all.12081</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23253182</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Allergy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">68</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>25991</offset><text>Maternal and newborn vitamin D status and its impact on food allergy development in the German LINA cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">856</infon><infon key="lpage">861</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stenberg Hammar;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Hedlin;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Konradsen;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Nordlund;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Kull;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Giske;given-names:CG</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/apa.12666</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24766450</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Acta Paediatr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">103</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>26104</offset><text>Subnormal levels of vitamin D are associated with acute wheeze in young children</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">147</infon><infon key="lpage">153</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Baïz;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dargent-Molina;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wark;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Souberbielle;given-names:J-C</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Annesi-Maesano;given-names:I</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2013.05.017</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23810764</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">133</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>26185</offset><text>Cord serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D and risk of early childhood transient wheezing and atopic dermatitis</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1108</infon><infon key="lpage">10.e2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Visness;given-names:CM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sandel;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:O'Connor;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gern;given-names:JE</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Jaffee;given-names:KF</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Wood;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2015.03.046</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25979524</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">136</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>26285</offset><text>Cord blood vitamin D concentrations are unrelated to atopy and wheeze in 2 diverse birth cohort studies</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">834</infon><infon key="lpage">837</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Koistinen;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Turunen;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Vuorinen;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Söderlund-Venermo;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Ruuskanen;given-names:O</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/pai.12308</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25387768</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatr Allergy Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>26389</offset><text>Vitamin D, virus etiology, and atopy in first-time wheezing children in Finland</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">337</infon><infon key="lpage">343</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chiu;given-names:CY</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:SY</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Peng;given-names:YC</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tsai;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hua;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yao;given-names:TC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/pai.12384</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25847488</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatr Allergy Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>26469</offset><text>Maternal vitamin D levels are inversely related to allergic sensitization and atopic diseases in early childhood</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">38</infon><infon key="lpage">43</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stelmach;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Majak;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jerzynska;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Podlecka;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Stelmach;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Polańska;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2014.10.016</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25468413</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Respir Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">109</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>26582</offset><text>Cord serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D correlates with early childhood viral-induced wheezing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">133</infon><infon key="lpage">138</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Martinez;given-names:FD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wright;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Taussig;given-names:LM</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Holberg;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Halonen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Morgan;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJM199501193320301</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7800004</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">332</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>26668</offset><text>Asthma and wheezing in the first six years of life</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">456</infon><infon key="lpage">461</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liao;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lai;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yeh;given-names:KW</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huang;given-names:YL</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yao;given-names:TC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Tsai;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/pai.12247</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25171739</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatr Allergy Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">25</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>26719</offset><text>Exclusive breastfeeding is associated with reduced cow's milk sensitization in early childhood</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e0142797</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lai;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liao;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yao;given-names:TC</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tsai;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hua;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yeh;given-names:KW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0142797</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26559673</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS ONE</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>26814</offset><text>Respiratory function in healthy Taiwanese infants: tidal breathing analysis, passive mechanics, and tidal forced expiration</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1969</infon><infon key="lpage">1972</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Emmen;given-names:JMA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wielders;given-names:JPM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Boer;given-names:A-K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:van den Ouweland;given-names:JMW</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vader;given-names:HL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1515/cclm-2011-0085</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23113978</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Chem Lab Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>26938</offset><text>The new Roche vitamin D total assay: fit for its purpose?</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">125</infon><infon key="lpage">132</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hendolin;given-names:PH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Paulin;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ylikoski;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10618075</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Clin Microbiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">38</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>26996</offset><text>Clinically Applicable Multiplex PCR for Four Middle Ear Pathogens</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1251</infon><infon key="lpage">1252</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ren;given-names:CL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Robinson;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ranganathan;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1002/ppul.23012</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24574186</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatr Pulmonol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>27062</offset><text>Chloral hydrate sedation for infant pulmonary function testing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">731</infon><infon key="lpage">740</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Frey;given-names:U</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Coates;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Sly;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bates;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11106221</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>27125</offset><text>Specifications for equipment used for infant pulmonary function testing. ERS/ATS Task Force on Standards for Infant Respiratory Function Testing. European Respiratory Society/ American Thoracic Society</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1180</infon><infon key="lpage">1192</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bates;given-names:JH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schmalisch;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Filbrun;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11292125</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>27327</offset><text>Tidal breath analysis for infant pulmonary function testing. ERS/ATS Task Force on Standards for Infant Respiratory Function Testing. European Respiratory Society/American Thoracic Society</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">141</infon><infon key="lpage">148</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gappa;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Colin;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Goetz;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11307744</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">17</infon><infon key="year">2001</infon><offset>27516</offset><text>Passive respiratory mechanics: the occlusion techniques</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">741</infon><infon key="lpage">748</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Sly;given-names:PD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tepper;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Henschen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gappa;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11106222</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">16</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>27572</offset><text>Tidal forced expirations. ERS/ATS Task Force on Standards for Infant Respiratory Function Testing. European Respiratory Society/American Thoracic Society</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">529S</infon><infon key="lpage">533S</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Greer;given-names:FR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18689395</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Clin Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">88</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>27726</offset><text>25-Hydroxyvitamin D: functional outcomes in infants and young children</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">18</infon><infon key="lpage">28</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bischoff-Ferrari;given-names:HA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Giovannucci;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Willett;given-names:WC</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Dietrich;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Dawson-Hughes;given-names:B</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16825677</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Clin Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">84</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>27797</offset><text>Estimation of optimal serum concentrations of 25-hydroxyvitamin D for multiple health outcomes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">266</infon><infon key="lpage">281</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Holick;given-names:MF</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJMra070553</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17634462</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">357</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>27892</offset><text>Vitamin D Deficiency</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">n/a</infon><infon key="lpage">n/a</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Saraf;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Morton;given-names:SMB</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Grant;given-names:CC</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Matern Child Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>27913</offset><text>Global summary of maternal and newborn vitamin D status—a systematic review</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1093</infon><infon key="lpage">9.e1–5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Rothers;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wright;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Stern;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Halonen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2011.07.015</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21855975</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">128</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>27991</offset><text>Cord blood 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels are associated with aeroallergen sensitization in children from Tucson, Arizona</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8175898</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liao;given-names:SL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lai;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Tsai;given-names:MH</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hua;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yeh;given-names:KW</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Su;given-names:KW</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1155/2016/8175898</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27298518</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mediators Inflamm</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">2016</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>28109</offset><text>Maternal vitamin D level is associated with viral Toll-like receptor triggered IL-10 response but not the risk of infectious diseases in infancy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1336</infon><infon key="lpage">1343</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zosky;given-names:GR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Berry;given-names:LJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Elliot;given-names:JG</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:James;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gorman;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Hart;given-names:PH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1164/rccm.201010-1596OC</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21297070</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Respir Crit Care Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">183</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>28254</offset><text>Vitamin D deficiency causes deficits in lung function and alters lung structure</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e99856</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chawes;given-names:BL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bønnelykke;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jensen;given-names:PF</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Schoos;given-names:A-MM</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Heickendorff;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bisgaard;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0099856</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24925304</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS ONE</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>28334</offset><text>Cord blood 25(OH)-vitamin D deficiency and childhood asthma, allergy and eczema: the COPSAC2000 birth cohort study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">474</infon><infon key="lpage">485</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Cremers;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Thijs;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Penders;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jansen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mommers;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1136/thx.2010.151985</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21422038</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Thorax</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>28449</offset><text>Maternal and child's vitamin D supplement use and vitamin D level in relation to childhood lung function: the KOALA Birth Cohort Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1334</infon><infon key="lpage">1340</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Niruban;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Alagiakrishnan;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Beach;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Senthilselvan;given-names:A</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/ejcn.2014.121</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24986817</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur J Clin Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">68</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>28584</offset><text>Association of vitamin D with respiratory outcomes in Canadian children</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1019</infon><infon key="lpage">1026</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Larose;given-names:TL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Langhammer;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chen;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Camargo;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Romundstad;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Mai;given-names:X-M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1183/09031936.00069714</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25395037</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">45</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>28656</offset><text>Serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels and lung function in adults with asthma: the HUNT Study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2154</infon><infon key="lpage">2159</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Carlsen;given-names:K-H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carlsen;given-names:KL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7713196</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>28745</offset><text>Tidal breathing analysis and response to salbutamol in awake young children with and without asthma</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">661</infon><infon key="lpage">675</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Taussig;given-names:LM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wright;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Holberg;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Halonen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Morgan;given-names:WJ</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Martinez;given-names:FD</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">12704342</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">111</infon><infon key="year">2003</infon><offset>28845</offset><text>Tucson children's respiratory study: 1980 to present</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">763</infon><infon key="lpage">768</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Modl;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Eber;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Weinhandl;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Gruber;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Zach;given-names:MS</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1164/ajrccm.161.3.9812063</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10712319</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Respir Crit Care Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">161</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>28898</offset><text>Assessment of bronchodilator responsiveness in infants with bronchiolitis. A comparison of the tidal and the raised volume rapid thoracoabdominal compression technique</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1682</infon><infon key="lpage">1689</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Håland;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carlsen;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Sandvik;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Devulapalli;given-names:CS</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Munthe-Kaas;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pettersen;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1056/NEJMoa052885</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17050892</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">N Engl J Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">355</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>29066</offset><text>Reduced Lung Function at Birth and the Risk of Asthma at 10 Years of Age</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">151</infon><infon key="lpage">157</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Young;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Arnott;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:O'Keeffe;given-names:PT</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Le Souëf;given-names:PN</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Landau;given-names:LI</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10678638</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Eur Respir J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>29139</offset><text>The association between early life lung function and wheezing during the first 2 yrs of life</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">78</infon><infon key="lpage">91</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lum;given-names:S</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Paediatric Pulmonary Function Testing</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>29232</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">190</infon><infon key="lpage">196</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bailey;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Veljkovic;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yazdanpanah;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Adeli;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2012.10.037</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23153571</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Biochem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">46</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>29233</offset><text>Analytical measurement and clinical relevance of vitamin D(3) C3-epimer</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">816</infon><infon key="lpage">822</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bailey;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Perumal;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yazdanpanah;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Mahmud Al;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Baqui;given-names:AH</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Adeli;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2014.01.015</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24462965</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Clin Biochem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">47</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>29305</offset><text>Maternal-fetal-infant dynamics of the C3-epimer of 25-hydroxyvitamin D</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">93</infon><infon key="lpage">101</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:van Etten;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mathieu;given-names:C</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jsbmb.2005.06.002</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16046118</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">97</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>29376</offset><text>Immunoregulation by 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3: basic concepts</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2909</infon><infon key="lpage">2912</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:TT</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nestel;given-names:FP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bourdeau;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Nagai;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wang;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Liao;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15322146</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">173</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>29437</offset><text>Cutting edge: 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 is a direct inducer of antimicrobial peptide gene expression</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">234</infon><infon key="lpage">238</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:White;given-names:JH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jsbmb.2010.03.034</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20302931</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">121</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>29537</offset><text>Vitamin D as an inducer of cathelicidin antimicrobial peptide expression: past, present and future</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">239</infon><infon key="lpage">245</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gunville;given-names:CF</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mourani;given-names:PM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Ginde;given-names:AA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">23782205</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Inflamm Allergy Drug Targets</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">12</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>29636</offset><text>The role of vitamin D in prevention and treatment of infection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">52</infon><infon key="lpage">58.e5</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brehm;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Schuemann;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fuhlbrigge;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hollis;given-names:BW</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Strunk;given-names:RC</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Zeiger;given-names:RS</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2010.03.043</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20538327</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Allergy Clin Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">126</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>29699</offset><text>Serum vitamin D levels and severe asthma exacerbations in the Childhood Asthma Management Program study</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1255</infon><infon key="lpage">1260</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Urashima;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Segawa;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Okazaki;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kurihara;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Wada;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Ida;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.29094</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20219962</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Clin Nutr</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">91</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>29803</offset><text>Randomized trial of vitamin D supplementation to prevent seasonal influenza A in schoolchildren</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">e99105</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yao;given-names:TC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tu;given-names:YL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chang;given-names:SW</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tsai;given-names:HJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gu;given-names:PW</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Ning;given-names:HC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0099105</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24892430</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">PLoS ONE</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">9</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>29899</offset><text>Suboptimal vitamin D status in a population-based study of Asian children: prevalence and relation to allergic diseases and atopy</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">152</infon><infon key="lpage">158</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:YW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Chen;given-names:CK</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wang;given-names:LJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24909252</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Psychiatr Danub</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">26</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>30029</offset><text>Is suicide mortality associated with meteorological and socio-economic factors? An ecological study in a city in Taiwan with a high suicide rate</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">304</infon><infon key="lpage">331</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Gappa;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rabbette;given-names:PS</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Costeloe;given-names:KL</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8327290</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Pediatr Pulmonol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">15</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>30174</offset><text>Assessment of passive respiratory compliance in healthy preterm infants: a critical evaluation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1451</infon><infon key="lpage">1458</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Dundas;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Dezateux;given-names:CA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fletcher;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jackson;given-names:EA</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Stocks;given-names:J</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Am J Respir Crit Care Med</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">151</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>30269</offset><text>Comparison of single-breath and plethysmographic measurements of resistance in infancy</text></passage></document></collection>
